Guide to the A. B. C. Walker Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
A. B. C. Walker papers
1983-1990
SC0658
Walker, A. B. C.
18 Linear feet
Collection pertains to his research and teaching and includes grant files (proposals, budgets, correspondence, etc.); photographs of stellar phenomena (prints and negatives); drawings, graphs, charts and computer printouts; and files from the classes he taught at Stanford.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Arthur B. C. Walker, an innovative astrophysicist and a mentor of women and minority students, was a professor of applied physics at Stanford University from January 1974 until his death in 2001. He earned his B.S. in physics at Case Institute of Technology in 1957 and his Ph.D. at the University of Illinois in 1962. After completing his doctorate, he served 3 years in the U.S. Air Force at the Weapons Laboratory and then joined the Space Physics Laboratory of the Aerospace Corporation. At Stanford, Walker constructed, launched, and carried out observations of the Sun's Corona in successive rocket launched payload experiments.
Description of the Collection
Collection pertains to his research and teaching and includes grant files (proposals, budgets, correspondence, etc.); photographs of stellar phenomena (prints and negatives); drawings, graphs, charts and computer printouts; and files from the classes he taught at Stanford.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Department of Physics. Faculty.; Walker, A. B. C.; Astronomical instruments.; Sun--Corona.; X-ray astronomy.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2002-316
    CSSA – Center for Space Science and Astrophysics (SU)
    ASO – Advance solar observatory
  - Research grant files: proposals, budgets, correspondence, etc.
    - Polarimeter (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Water Window Imaging X-Ray Microscope for Cancer Research, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Proposal CSSA 1990-13 (Cosmic X-Ray Rocket Spectrograph) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Scherrer proposal info (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Timothy proposal info (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - HRSO 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous letters - proposals (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - NAS8-36481 MSFC (Dev. Of Normal Incidence X-Ray Optic for XUV Soft X-Ray Spec.) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Old misc. proposal materials (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wolter-Cassegrain/Wolter-Gregorian X-Ray Telescope Systems, May 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - [Unlabelled – mostly re contract fee] (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - [Unlabelled – assorted proposals] (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - X-ray Optics for High Resolution Heliospect. CSSA 89-07 (July 1989) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - X-ray Optics for High Resolution Heliospect. CSSA 89-07 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - X-ray Optics for High Resolution Heliospect. CSSA 88-04 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - CSSA-04 (X-Ray Optics) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - [X-ray Optics for High Resolution Heliospect. – title pages] (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - [X-ray Optics for High Resolution Heliospect. – appendix D?] (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 88-04 (ESS-025) 3/1/89-2/90 (X-ray Optics for High Resolution Heliospect.) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - NSG5131 Imaging Solar Corona (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Spectroscopic Imaging of the Solar Corona (CSSA 88-18) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - UHRXS Space Station (Part I) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - UHRXS Space Station (Information; correspondence) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - UHRXS Space Station (Part II and annex) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - CSSA-88-16 Enhancement of Student Observatory (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Advanced Solar Observatory (CSSA 88-15) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - I Technical ASO (A Solar/Stellar Coronal Explorer) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - II Management ASO (A Solar/Stellar Coronal Explorer) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - ASO correspondence (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - ASO letters 7/88 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - ASO 5/6/88 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Advanced Solar Observatory (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - ASO technical paper (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Latest original 9/27 [ASO items] (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - CSSA 9-88 [ASO] (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Support of the Fabrication, Test and Operation of the MAMA Detectors for the CDS, SUMER and UVCS Instruments on the SOHO Mission, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - SC Explorer AO (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - [Small Class Explorer] (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Part 1 technical – no pictures (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Part II management no appendices (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - [unlabelled materials] (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Frontispiece slide (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 90-15 Modification to the Ultra-High Resolution XUV Spectraheliogram (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Handle Now [related to proposals] (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - [Proposal 90-13 Cosmic x-ray Rocket Spectrograph] (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - [Proposal 90-14 Initiation of a Conceptual Design Study for the Ultra-High Resolution XUV Spectroheliograph in Response to a MSFC Request] (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - ATM S-O56 Proposal (x-ray telescope) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - CSSA 88-09 Solar/Stellar Coronal Explorer (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - SSEC (Explorer) CSSA 9-88 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - SSCE (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Dick Monroe material, Ball Aerospace (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - CSSA 87-18: file copy/original (Spec. Imaging of the Solar Corona) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - CSSA 87-18: extra copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Active Sun Telescope Array proposal 5/5/88 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Rocket budget and program plans 4/85 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - X-Ray Spectroscopy of Extended Cosmic Sources (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - X-Ray Spectroscopy of the Solar Corona (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - NASA NSG 5131 Proposal, 9/6/1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Proposal CSSA 35A (Spec. Imaging of Galactic and Extra Galactic X-ray Sources) 3/1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Proposal 86-35: original (Cosmic x-ray Rocket Spectrograph) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - CSSA 86-36 sent 6/18/1987 (Spec. Imaging of the Solar Corona) (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - CSSA proposal 33-3151 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - NASA NCA2-IR745-412 (Constr. of a 0.1K Bolometer for Astro. Meas.) (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - HESP proposal May 1986 (CSSA 86-34) (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Proposal to the Max 90 Study Group for Soft x-ray/XUV spectroheliograph (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - NASA Spec. Studies of the Solar Corona (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - [Spectroscopic Imaging of the Solar Corona] (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - NCAR letters (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - [SOI Definition Phase Proposal] (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - [Miscellaneous] (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - MDI (Phil Scherrer) (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Proposal – Wilcox Observatory (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Optics and Camera Concepts for HESP 3/1985 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - A Soft X-Ray Spectroheliograph for HESP Feb. 1985 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - An Investigation to Study Solar Activity during the Maximum of Cycle 22, Vol. 1 and Vol. 2 (Box 2)
  - Photoprints and/or negatives
    - 27.092 PMTs
      - 44A° Test image (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 8 sec 173A° (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - [loose images] (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 64 sec 173A° (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 173A° 200 sec neg. print (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 256A° Herschelian, 4 sec (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Direct Wolter image (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Wolter-Cassegrain PMTs (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Hardware PMTs (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - 173A° Cassegrain Short Exposure
      - MSFC Calibration Images (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - [loose items] (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Cass I 4 sec (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Cass I 8 sec (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - 173A° Cassegrain 64 sec
      - Cass I 64 sec 5x7 inch medium contrast (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Cass I 64 sec low to medium contrast, full 35 mm frame (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Cass I 64 sec low contrast (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - 173A° Cassegrain 64 sec
      - 173A° Cass. 200 sec high contrast (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Cass I 200 sec Ilford 8x10 inch medium contrast (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Cass I 200 sec low to medium contrast, full 35 mm frame (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Cass I 200 sec low contrast (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Cass I 200 sec negative print (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - 173A° 200 sec full frame (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - 173A° Cassegrain color 64 sec exposure
      - 64 sec color no label, low grain (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - 173A° Cassegrain color 200 sec exposure
      - 200 sec color (4/88) with label (low grain) (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - 200 sec color 4x5 inch with label (low grain) (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - 200 sec color 4x5 inch no label (low grain) (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - 200 sec color, negative print with label (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - 200 sec color, negative print no label (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - 200 sec medium contrast 3x5 inch (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - 173A° Cassegrain color MSFC digitized
      - 173A° Cass MSFC digitized image (yellow) (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Cass I MSFC digitized version (blue) (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - 173A° Cass MSFC digitized laplacion filter (orange) (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 173A° Cassegrain miscellaneous
      - Cass I 200 sec color with label (grainy) (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Cass I 200 sec color no label (grainy) (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - 173A° Cassegrain interneg slides, transparencies
      - 173A° solar diagrams (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - 173A° Cass 4x5 interneg, b/w (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - 173A° 4x5 interneg 4x5 color 64 sec with label (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - 173A° Cass. Interneg 4x5 color 200 sec with label (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - 173A° Cass 4x5 interneg, color, misc. (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Cass I 200 sec 35 mm slides (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - 256A° Cassegrain
      - 256A° Cassegrain 64 sec exp. (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - 256A° Cass 64 sec small format (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - 256A° Herschelian
      - 256A° Herschelian 8 sec exp frame #11 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - 256A° Herschelian bright print (exp is 4 or 8 seconds) (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - 256A° Herschelian color 8 sec with label (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - 256A° Herschelian color 8 sec no label (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - 256A° Herschelian 8 sec color 4x5 inch (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - 256A° Herschelian 8 sec color interneg 4x5 inch (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - 256A° Herschelian color overhead transparency (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - 256A° Herschelian slides (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - 44A° Wolter-Cassegrain WC-B
      - Camera #6 44A° Frame VI 16 sec (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Camera #6 44A° Frame VI 64 sec (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - 175A° Wolter-Cassegrain WC-D
      - Camera #8 WC-D Frame VIII 8 sec (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Camera #8 WC-D Frame VIII 9,16 sec (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Wolter Prime Focus
      - Camera #9 IX 20 200 sec (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Drawings (misc.) for 27.092
      - [loose drawings] (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - WCFA drawings (copies) (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - WCSA, TFC drawings (copies) (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Drawings (misc) (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - Cassegrain drawings (copies) (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - SMT drawings (copies) (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - Obsolete drawings (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Drawings HZ 43
      - Drawings HZ 43 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Multilayer Calculations for 27.092
      - Theoretical Multilayer data, 6/24/1986 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - X-ray Telescope Specifics
      - Efficiency of Telescope Optics 4-25 A° (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - Solar spectrum at diff. temp. through solpol mirrors (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - Solar spectrum through rocket mirrors (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - [unlabeled] (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - Shutter (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Ross Filters
      - Ross filter thickness tradeoff calculations (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Ross Filters 1
      - Solar lines for Ross filters (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - Cr - Va (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - Fe – Mn (Box 4, Folder 72)
      - Co – Fe (Box 4, Folder 73)
      - Ni – Co (Box 4, Folder 74)
      - Cu – Ni; W. solar flux final results (Box 4, Folder 75)
      - Zn – Cu (Box 4, Folder 76)
      - Al – Mg (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - Si – Al (Box 4, Folder 78)
      - Misc. Ross filter transmission spectra (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - Sample substrate spectra (Box 4, Folder 80)
      - Cu – Ni Optimal series no solar flux (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Ross Filters 2
      - Cu – Ni Optimal series solar flux (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - Cu – Ni +/- 5% w. solar flux (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - Cu – Ni transmission spectra (early) (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Proposals 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Proposal 88-09 Solar/Stellar Coronal Explorer (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Rocket proposal 1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - SR & T proposals 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Proposal 87-18 Spectroscopic Imaging of the Solar Corona (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - UHRXS files [Ultra-High Resolution XUV Spectroheliograph] (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Statements of work for UHRXS (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - UHRXS renewal proposal and progress reports (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Part I: Technical proposal (11/88) [UHRXS] (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Part II: Management cost plan [UHRXS] (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Astro EUV/X-R Observatory on the Moon (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Abstracts 1343 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - [Multi-spectral Solar Telescope Array – various article drafts] (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Astro 150 outline, Spring 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - [Astro 100 Lab Manual, 1986] (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Extras [class experiments, manuals etc.] (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - AP015 final exam winter quarter 1986-87 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - AP015 midterm 1986-87 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - AP015 - miscellanesou (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - AP015 problem sets winter quarter 1988-89 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Astro/AP 050/100/356 outlines (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Astro 050 course description (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Astro 356 course description (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Astro 050/100 course description 1989 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - [AP015 problem sets] (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Astro 100 experiment summaries (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - AP015 outline winter quarter 1987 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - [AP/AST015 problem sets] (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - AP015 winter quarter 1988-89 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - AP015 midterm 2/88 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Astro/AP 356 class description grad students (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - AP015 outline winter quarter 1987-88 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - AP050 course description 1986 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Astronomy 050 course listings 1986 summer (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Astronomy 050 course description (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Astronomy 050 "intro" (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Astronomy 050 outline (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Astronomy 100 course description 1986 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Film: Black Brant, W/O #0622-M N067, June 29, 1983 (16mm color) (Box 5, Folder o1)
  - Slides: 27.092 Nike Black Brant horiz. Check w/o S-0055 (Box 5, Folder o2)